i woke up this morning to a half a dozen
different friends having emailed me this
article um
and uh there were accompanying
expressions of shock that's the only
word i can really think of to use here
is is shock
mike isikoff is a pulitzer prize-winning
investigative journalist he's worked at
the biggest most important best funded
news outlets in america the guy's a
serious journalist
and uh you know for mike isikoff to say
something as definitive
as the cia was trying to murder julian
assange or to capture julian assange and
then to go into detail of exactly how
they were planning to do that you have
to take that very seriously he
interviews
more than 30 current and former cia
officers and former administration
officials who were privy to this
information it's so well sourced
99 of it it's so well covered
that i i have to believe it we we know
that that the cia was obsessed that
pompeo specifically was obsessed with
julian assange and wikileaks because of
the vault seven revelations that was
that was akin to
the the crown jewels of the 19 mid 1970s
uh being released and by god
uh uh pompeo and
gina haspel were determined to put an
end to julian assange and to put an end
to wikileaks so it wasn't just these
insane plans to murder assange but there
were accompanying plans to infiltrate
and to neutralize
wikileaks as an organization and
isikoff says in the article that the cia
had some success
in infiltrating wikileaks in um in
collecting information from inside the
organization in determining wikileaks
future plans and intentions uh they they
really targeted wikileaks directly and
went after wikileaks
so you know disruption is the easy part
collection against wikileaks is the easy
part i'm stuck on this murder plot
this is just so
you know if if i were still at the cia
if this were 2004
and somebody said
oh listen we're gonna we're gonna plan
to murder this australian national
because he keeps publishing our stuff
and we don't like his politics
that would have been like a bad joke i
mean i i don't even know anybody in 2004
who would have said words like that out
loud it's just so outrageous and now you
know we read it and we say wow you know
cia they were pretty mad
but uh this is what they do they have to
go after wikileaks no this this whole
thing bothers me there were a couple of
revelations in this piece kevin that
were very very disturbing to me to the
point where
like i am i i'm having trouble wrapping
my brain around it for example
they talked about the possibility of
having to engage in a shootout
in the streets of london
outside the ecuadorian embassy they
talked about the possibility of shooting
the tires out of a russian diplomatic
plane
so it couldn't lift off
from an airport outside london if julian
assange had been on the plane
okay these are acts of war you can't do
things like this and then almost as an
aside isakoff says uh the british agreed
that they would be the do with the ones
doing the shooting
well that doesn't make it any less of an
act of war if if julian assange had been
released for example and if he had uh
been granted asylum in russia and if the
russians had sent a plane to pick him up
that is a diplomatic vehicle
right it has all the same diplomatic
protections that an embassy would or an
embassy car would you can't shoot the
tires out
that is like firing a rocket at
the russian mainland you just can't do
things like that
but apparently
mike pompeo was so obsessed with taking
down julian assange that that's exactly
what they were planning to do now
there is a way
at the cia that you go about doing
something like this first of all you
have to declare a person a clear and
present uh
danger to the united states
it appears that that's what they did
with julian they they said he is a clear
and present danger to the safety and
security of the united states and as
such he has to be executed
but he's an australian national he's an
australian national and australia is one
of the five eyes countries
and so
the united states would have had to
bring the australians in on the
operation they would have had to have
australian permission
to go ahead and murder an australian
national there's no paragraph saying the
australian said now
pompeo wait a minute
he's an australian national
and while we don't like him either you
can't kill an australian national we
didn't see any of that
so what are we supposed to conclude that
the us did not inform australia or the
that the australians were in on it now
um
it says in the article that the british
certainly were in on it that the british
were the ones who agreed to shoot out
the russian planes or to carry out the
the gun battle that would have taken
place in front of the the ecuadorian
embassy
does that mean australia has changed too
and the australians were willing to
allow the british and the americans to
conspire to murder one of their
nationals
so number one you've got to get
permission from the
the justice department's office of legal
counsel it appears that they got that
number two you would have to get the
agreement of the australian government
it appears that they got that too
uh number three
and this is one that sort of makes me
want to swallow my tongue
uh you have to get the approval of the
congressional oversight committees
now if they were serious about this
operation and the planning for the
operation went as far as it did
that means that they got the permission
of the oversight committees i complain a
lot in a lot of interviews that the
oversight committees are little more
than cheerleaders for the cia and
they've been little more than
cheerleaders from the cia since the
1990s
but this is ridiculous
this is murder
murder of a of an australian national
murder of somebody who has never been
convicted uh in a u.s court of
committing any crime
in fact the british courts deemed his
the accusation of his crime is not even
worthy of of extradition
so
you know the revelations in this article
if if they're even half true and like i
say he interviewed something like 30
former cia people and administration
officials we have to believe him i mean
this is just
over the top the fact that they were
talking about killing him but then also
seriously considering a rendition
operation against
uh uh uh uh an editor a publisher of a
media organization this is insane
shooting out the the
the tires of a russian diplomatic flight
that would have you know taken him into
exile in russia you can't do that you
might as well shoot the plane down out
of the sky it's an act of war you can't
do it
you know we see these cute little scenes
on law and order where they trick this
iranian diplomatic car into opening its
doors and they grab the guy out of the
diplomatic car that doesn't happen in
real life you can't do that because then
what's going to happen if the russians
decide to shoot the wheels shoot out the
tires of an american diplomatic plane
or to violate american diplomatic uh
sovereignty maybe go into a classified
diplomatic pouch
you can't
do things like that
so the fact that it went all the way to
the president wow i i don't even have
words
so
uh
so yeah i mean when you add in the fbi's
informant when you add in the fbi's
information you add in what the cia's
conduct is in this and then also i
should mention um the fbi stole julian
assange's legally privileged materials
we know that he confiscated
yeah all that together there is no
reason
why this case should still be
going no
any
any criminal defense attorney
of any repute at all should be able to
pick this case apart in a day
the entire the government's entire case
is based on a convicted pedophiles lies
now he for whatever reason
he
he confessed to uh to a
an icelandic uh journalist
that he lied about his access to julian
assange he lied about his position in
wikileaks he embezzled money from
wikileaks and then went on to molest
young boys and was convicted of
pedophilia and that's their star witness
you